PROFILE

Experienced in a wide variety of modern technologies, I enjoy constantly expanding and improving my skill set in different market sectors. A good communicator, I am able to rapidly assimilate new/unfamiliar concepts, explain to others in jargon-free terms, and set about productive development.

SKILL SET

- Virtualization (Docker, AWS ECS/EKS, Kubernetes, VMWare)
- Continuous Integration & Delivery (Jenkins, Bamboo and GO)
- Linux (RedHat/CentOS, Ubuntu/Debian, busybox/Alpine) and Solaris
- Cloud Providers AWS, Rackspace Cloud, Linode, Digital Ocean
- Puppet (w/ hieradata) & Vagrant. Infrastructure as Code, Terraform
- Monitoring Nagios/Icinga, Sensu, Prometheus
- Source control svn, git, tfs, github, bitbucket
- Apache Tomcat, jetty, Apache httpd, Weblogic, nginx, HAProxy
- Java (with Spring & Hibernate), Groovy, Ruby, awk, perl, bash
- JSP, GWT, Freemarker, HTML, XML, CSS, Javascript
- Spring MVC, Dropwizard, Play Framework
- MySQL, Oracle, SQL server, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, Gluster, AWS RDS
- Test Driven Development, Unit testing (JUnit), Cucumber, Selenium.
- Build systems: ant, maven, gradle. Artifactory for artifact storage.
- Agile methodology Kanban, Mingle, Jira, Pivotal, basecamp
- Operational knowledge of VPNs, dhcp, mail transport (postfix), ssh, ftp

WORK EXPERIENCE

SafeGuard Global (Sandbach, Cheshire) Apr 2019 - present

Key skills: Terraform/Docker/Amazon ECS, Jenkins CI & CD

DevOps Engineer (contract) - duties include:

- Responsibility for design and implementation of new cloud infrastructure (AWS) & CI/CD pipeline (Jenkins).
- Complete Terraform migration of AWS infrastructure into codebase.
- Java microservices, using Docker Linux containers deployed in Amazon ECS, using ALBs, API gateways & serverless/lambdas, Elasticache, RDS.
- Deployment of APM tool (Dynatrace) for monitoring & observability.
- Additionally, automated Windows Server builds in AWS, using terraform + chocolatey

MoneySuperMarket.com (Ewloe, Wales) Apr 2013 - Mar 2019

Key skills: Java/Groovy/Ruby, MongoDB, Puppet/Linux/Vagrant/Docker/Kubernetes, Jenkins CI & CD

Role 5: Technical Lead - DevOps Platform, Sep 2016 - Mar 2019

- Infrastructure architecture design for cloud-based applications in AWS
- Technical design of DevOps patterns to be used throughout the business
- Oversee major security projects to roll-out encryption at rest and in-flight across our entire cloud estate.
- Manage a team of 5 DevOps engineers, 1000+ EC2/Containers
- Involved in root cause analysis following live site incidents.

Role 4: Inline DevOps Engineer, Aggregation squad, Jan 2015 - Sep 2016

- Support day-to-day operations + deployments in the AWS cloud environment.
- Collaborate with team in building and deploying new business functionality.
- Enhance and improve security and resilience of infrastructure, build new infrastructure components

Role 3: Technical Lead, Sales Data, Jan - Dec 2014

- 11 month project to build a highly performant, non-blocking, automated application to process, validate and
 disseminate incoming data representing provider sales. Objectives included a high level of data-driven
 configuration in order to remove future need for development effort when adding new sales channels,
 providers, data specifications, matching rules.
- CI/CD: Wrote build tooling and deployment code in Groovy & Gradle.
- Wrote puppet manifests for server provisioning
- Collaborated with Stakeholders and B.A. to decide each phase' goals, story breakdown and size estimation.
- Worked with P.M. to ensure resourcing and unblocking of issues
- Worked with Solution Architect to decide technologies used and strategies for application deployment.
- Formulated MySQL configuration for persistence layer, in collaboration with data Architect.
- Managed small team of 3 developers & testers
- Java 7 with Play Framework/Akka.
- Automated testing using cucumber as part of continuous integration/delivery.

Role 2: DevOps for .NET stack, Oct - Dec 2013

• Built end-to-end (using GO & Ruby) deployment pipelines for .NET codebases - including automated testing.

Role 1: Java/DevOps - 'Easy Checkout' project, April - Sep 2013

- In a team of 2, developing a single-page, RESTful web app Java (server-side) + javascript front-end.
- Implemented roll-out to multiple AWS regions, including automated provisioning of required infrastructure via AWS Ruby SDK.
- Implemented Java-based analytics API, with HA MySQL backend & JMS queue buffering messages for maximum resilience.

Business partner, C&J Software. (Parkgate, England) Feb 2013 - present

Key skills: Java/Spring/Hibernate/GWT, Freemarker, Virtualisation (Linode), nagios, Tomcat, MySQL, Shibboleth SAML SP

- Run a business which supplies Events Calendaring software and support to Universities.
- Java & GWT system provides a workflow & permission-based editor allowing SSO authenticated users ability
 to enter events, tagged by user-defined criteria. Events flow from the publishing system via a data feed to a
 public viewer based on freemarker templates. Viewer also includes an API returning XML or JSON and
 allowing rich query parameters in order to allow multiple subsites to include specific-interest content on their
 own pages.
- System hosted in the cloud (Linode) and monitored by Nagios instances in EC2 and Digital ocean.
- Provide consulting to London-based third party developing Java/Weblogic/Solaris application for City investment bank.

Development & Operations Manager, Columba Systems ltd. (London) Jan 2005 - Feb 2013

Key skills: Java/Spring/Hibernate/GWT, Linux, Virtualisation (LXC, VMware, Xen), scripting, nagios, Tomcat

- Designed and implemented roll-out for reliable, customer-facing data-feed processes as well as SaaS web
 applications, and associated infrastructure, for both internal and external clients, on a mix of physical, virtual
 and cloud-based servers. Including automated monitoring, off-site backups & data replication. Hands-on with
 Linux, virtualisation, monitoring, web containers.
- Extensive agile development experience with Java/Spring, both on back-end services (JPA/Hibernate) and web tier using MVC and MVP design patterns.
- Design of database objects and structure for internal and client application. Administration of in house databases for MySQL, Oracle 11g, SQL server, Sybase.
- Involved in the full application life-cycle from requirements analysis, design, architecture, development, testing, maintenance and deployment.
- Managed integration of applications inside data centres of several City investment institutions.
- Assisted with recruiting and training new staff.
- Instrumental in introducing and implementing several best practices :
 - defined deployment practices
 - defined QA/testing practices
 - defined disaster recovery policy and guidelines

My efforts not only in software development, but also in helping to drive improvements in best practices and quality assurance, willingness to mentor colleagues and providing guidance to enhance the business, have been acknowledged by the managers, directors and colleagues in the company.

HR Systems Officer, Stonham Housing Association (London) Sep 2002 - Jan 2005

Key skills: database design, SQL queries, database forms and reports, requirements gathering, specifications,

- Organised requirements gathering, specification documentation and evaluation of commercial HR & Payroll systems for a public sector organisation of 2500 employees.
- Designed processes around gathering, cleanup and transfer of paper based records into electronic format for import into chosen product.
- When the commercial product was delayed in purchase sign-off indefinitely as an interim solution I entirely designed, developed and implemented my own multi-user HR database, with input forms and reports tools. I trained 30 staff in 5 regional centres in the use of the system. The system was deployed and remained in use for over 5 years until the Housing Association was subsumed by its parent organisation.

The HR director and 5 regional Heads of HR all acknowledged my significant contribution to the improvement of the HR function and reporting abilities, despite the restriction of the initial circumstances.

Technical Specialist (3 month contract), Holon Corporation, (Sydney) Jan - Mar 2002

Key skills: Microsoft T-SQL, MS SQL server, Windows 2000 server

Senior Analyst Programmer, SAM business systems (London) 1998 – 2001

Key skills: PL/SQL, SQL, Pro*C, awk, shell, Oracle Forms and Reports, SCO Unix

Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Astrophysics Group, University College London, 1995 - 1998

Research into chemically peculiar stars (Hg-Mn stars)

Attended international conferences and workshops to present research results and give talks to other scientists. Published papers in prestigious peer-reviewed journals.

Teaching duties for undergraduate students & tour guide at the observatory.

Postdoctoral Research Assistant, School of Physics and Astronomy, St Andrews University, 1994 - 1995

• Research into Hydrogen-deficient stars; publishing several papers in international journals.

EDUCATION

PhD Astronomy, University College London — 1989-1993

BSc Astronomy, University College London — 1986-1989

4 'A' levels, Woodhouse Sixth Form College, London — 1984-1986

8 'O' levels, Friern Barnet County school, London — 1979-1984

16 Hawthorn Road, Parkgate, Neston, CH64 6SX